Debra Watkins

Web Development

503.432.6607



debwatins2@gmail.com



Portland, OR



SKILLS

Customer Support/Happiness
Recruiting/training teams
Conflict Resolution
Public Speaking
Grant Writing
Project Management
Social Media/Blogging

HTML5 CSS3

JavaScript

jQuery

WordPress

Bootstrap

Sketch

Git/Git Hub

Command Line

EDUCATION

PSYCHOLOGY University of Nevada, Reno

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Free Code Camp Udemy Practical Javascript Harvard CS50

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am an experienced and accomplished entrepreneur looking to utilize my 10+ years of superior customer service, project management, recruiting/training teams, public speaking and crisis management. It is my desire to leverage these skills along with my coding education into a junior developer/web development position.

Portfolio



Git Hub



Facebook



Twitter



EXPERIENCE

Freelancer

Created with Coffee & Code || October 2016 to Present Along with my coding classes I have been creating landing pages, websites and newsletters for local small businesses.

COO

Watkins Restoration & Restyling | January 2007 to July 2016

- Created a customer outreach program that provided pictures, videos and "live-feeds" so that customers could stay in touch and be involved in their projects. Increased customer retention 73%.
- Built website from template with e-commerce. Increased restoration inquiries by 48%. Increased parts sales by 66%.
- Created a searchable database of parts suppliers to make parts searches more efficient.

Owner/Pastry Chef/Cake Designer

White Rose Bakery | May 2002 to July 2014

- Instituted a customer happiness program, retained over 40% of clients through five years.
- Built template based website, increased sales 43%
- Met with potential couples. Provided an upscale experience, booked 83%.
- Instituted a project management system to assure that no details were missed.

Pastry Chef/Management Team

Stanford Sierra Camp | March 2000 to July 2002

- Worked with chef on large projects, weddings/events for up to 450 guest.
- Assisted in recruiting/training/managing new kitchen crew every 4 months.
- Instituted a guest happiness program with a database of allergies, favorite dishes, birthdays and anniversaries.

Psychiatric Emergency Services/Case Manager

El Dorado County Mental Health

- Developed and presented workshops on Conflict Management: workplace, school and relationships.
- Responded to emergency room & law enforcement requests for 5150 evals.
- Assisted mentally ill clients in independent living skills and placement.